# **Venuprasad Naik**

☑ vpnaik97@gmail.com	<b>=</b> +91 72598 16840
in linkedin.com/in/venuprasad	

# **Summary**

Inquisitive Programmer with experience of 2+ years in Software Development. Skilled in core Java, spring framework, Application Development, Maven, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), and React.js. I keep myself updated with new technologies and try to produce optimal code solutions. At Mercedes Benz research and development received 'Young Achiever of the Year' award.

# **Experience**



#### **Core Java Developer**

Jul 2019- Present

Mercedes-Benz Research and Development India

1 year 5 months

- Working on developing In-house software application for ECU Development that operates 24x7 using Core Java, Spring Security, Spring Boot, Maven, MS-SQL.
- Developed OpenID Connect (OIDC) login for Server Side Applications using Spring Framework.
- Contributed to page reorder pdf algorithm and table of content page algorithm.
- Worked on several backend code refactoring, optimization and performance improvement task.
- Developed Maven Library for Parsing Multidimensional Expressions and XML data.
- Produced High Quality software that is tested, code reviewed, analyzed in SonarQube, and checked in regularly for Continuous Integration.
- Familiar with tool like Jenkins, JFrog, Jira, Git, SonarQube.



#### **Graduate Engineer Trainee**

Aug 2018- Jul 2019

Mercedes-Benz Research and Development India

1 year

- Front End Developer for Developing a Web Application in React.js Framework with MobX.js and Axios.js using Typescript.
- Developed Analytical and Monitoring application for providing cloud-based billing solution to aid in various cloud solutions used in different projects using React.js, JSON, Fluent UI.
- Worked on Application KPI like Power BI for Web Application.
- Experience of working with Azure DevOps and Web API.
- Exposure to Azure dev test labs on a day to day basis.



#### **Mobile Application Developer (Intern)**

Jun 2017 - May 2018

AquaSafi Purification Systems

1 year

 Worked on Android Application for Internal NFC and External NFC using MifareClassic, ACR122u, java, SQLite, XML.

- Developed Text Message Authentication for Android Application for Activate, Deactivate and Tracking.
- Activation and Deactivation of App using Web Portal.
- Report generation and data sync to cloud

#### **Education**



### B V B College of Engineering & Technology, HUBLI

2014 - 2018

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Science and Engineering, CGPA-8.58



# M.E.S PU College, Sirsi

2012 - 2014

Pre-University Course, Computer Science, Aggregate -88.3%



# **GHS Shiraguni**

2009 - 2012

SSLC, High School/Secondary Certificate Programs, Aggregate -86.56%

#### **Skills**



Core Java • Jenkins • Git • SQL • Spring Framework • React.js • Software Development • JSON • Microsoft Azure • Maven

#### **Certifications**

# **Understanding Active Directory - Microsoft**

Aug 2017 - Present

# EMC Academic Associate, Information Storage and Management - Dell EMC

PJ44GN7Z2FB113C1 - Dec 2017 - Present

### Advanced Java Programming - LinkedIn

Jun 2019 – Present

# **Publication**

**Programmer Productivity Analyzer Tool -** IEEE International Conference on Computational Intelligence and Computing Research

Dec 15, 2017

### **Honors & Awards**

Young achiever of the Year 2020 - Mercedes-Benz Research and Development India

Nov 2020

# Sahyadri Young Ecologist Award 2012 - Indian Institute of Science

Jan 2012